<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>

<rss version="2.0">
<channel>

<title>Amber GRID-enabled web portal</title>
<description>GRID-enabled web portal to NMR structures refinement and molecular dynamic simulation of proteins based on Amber* Molecular Dynamics program suite</description>
<link>http://py-enmr.cerm.unifi.it/</link>
<lastBuildDate>Mon, 19 Jul 2010 10:30:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
<language>en-us</language>
<managingEditor>web-enmr@cerm.unifi.it (Ferella, Giachetti, Morelli, Rosato)</managingEditor>

<item>
    <title>New GRID-enabled Amber (with paramagnetic) web portal Launch</title>
    <link>http://py-enmr.cerm.unifi.it/</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">110234577</guid>
    <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jul 2010 10:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
    <description>
        <![CDATA[
	Dear all,<br />
                It is our pleasure to announce our new GRID-enabled Amber (with paramagnetic) we portal accessible
	from the following addresses:<br/>
	<br/>
	 <a href="http://py-enmr.cerm.unifi.it/">http://py-enmr.cerm.unifi.it/</a><br/>
	<br/>	
	<b>AMBER</b> is a collective name for a suite of programs that allow users to carry out molecular dynamics (MD) simulations on biological systems.
	The web-portal permits the creation and management of MD calculations from a web browser. The portal takes care also of all the grid accounting.
	A new user with her/his personal certificate installed in the browser can access to the portal from e-NMR web page and straightforwardly create
	a new user login and password. The site permits the creation of a new single calculation or the creation of a project where it will be possible
	to save a number of different calculations that belong to a common project (e.g. MD refinements of protein structures generated with different ensembles of restraints). 
	The user can select a pre-set MD refinement protocol to energy optimize NMR protein structures. The currently proposed protocol comprises four steps:
	<ul>
	    <li>
	In the first step the protein structure to be optimized is uploaded: this step corresponds to the amber leap program. Here it is possible to upload
	one pdb file, whose format will be automatically validated and converted into the format recognized by amber. If the interface detects some non
	standard residues or does not recognize some atoms in the pdb file, the user will be respectively asked to insert the topology and parameters for
	the non standard residue or presented with a warning showing the name of the atom(s) not recognized. During this step the user can add explicit water
	molecules to solvate the protein, add counter ions, insert new bonds for selected atoms (e.g. protein to metal). For NMR structures, which are typically
	represented by a bundle of 20-40 different conformers, this first step is carried out only for the first conformer and then automatically applied to all
	the structures in the bundle (which, at present, must be uploaded as a compressed tar file of the NMR bundle). For each structure in the bundle, an individual
	job is sent to the grid.
	    </li>
	    <li>
	    The second step manages the NMR restraints. Four types of restraint are allowed: NOE, dihedral angles, residual dipolar couplings (rdc’s)
	    and pseudocontact shifts (pcs). The last restraints are the so-called paramagnetic restraints. For all restraints it is possible to upload Xplor,
	    Dyana, or Cyana files. For paramagnetic restraints, it is possible to fit the anisotropy tensor directly in the web site.
	    </li>
	    <li>
	    The third step manages the setting of molecular dynamics calculations. The page can be visualized in a so-called basic mode and in an extended mode, which allows
	    users to view all the details of the amber settings. This step corresponds to the setup of the input to the sander program of the amber suite. As mentioned,
	    at this step it is possible to load a predefined sander protocol; nevertheless, this protocol can be modified by adding components from the menu in the left
	    part of the screen or by editing any single components in the panel on the right side.
	    </li>
	    <li>
	    The fourth and final step allows the user to give a name to the calculation started and submit it to the grid. When a grid job is started the web site
	    allows the user to check its status and to download the completed jobs using the Jobs menu. After the results of a job have been downloaded,
	    the user can browse them and download the various files.
	    </li>
	</ul>
	<br/>
	We hope that this web resource will be useful to the community and welcome any feedback (web-enmr@cerm.unifi.it).<br/>
	<br />
        <br />
        *The GRID-enabled web portal runs version 10 of Amber Molecular Dynamics package.
        ]]>
    </description>
</item>

<item>
    <title>Improved Multistructure management</title>
    <link>http://py-enmr.cerm.unifi.it/</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">110234577</guid>
    <pubDate>Mon, 13 Dec 2010 18:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    <description>
        <![CDATA[
	Dear all,<br/>
        it is our pleasure to announce that now is more easy manage a bundle of conformers. In fact the  GRID-enabled Amber (with paramagnetic) web portal
	will automatically detects bundle of conformers and will ask you if use it in simulation or none.
        ]]>
    </description>
</item>

<item>
    <title>Amber 11</title>
    <link>http://py-enmr.cerm.unifi.it/</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">110234577</guid>
    <pubDate>Tue, 14 Dec 2010 09:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    <description>
        <![CDATA[
	Dear all,<br/>
        it is our pleasure to announce that from now the <b>GRID-enabled Amber (with paramagnetic) web portal</b>
	use the version 11 of the Amber software suite. <br />
        ]]>
    </description>
</item>

<item>
    <title>Restart web GUI</title>
    <link>http://py-enmr.cerm.unifi.it/</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">110234577</guid>
    <pubDate>Wed, 15 Dec 2010 11:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    <description>
        <![CDATA[
	Dear all,<br/>
        it is our pleasure to announce that you can use the new web GUI to restart your jobs. Now you can run very long MD simulation with a few clicks.
        ]]>
    </description>
</item>

<item>
    <title>Filemanager web GUI</title>
    <link>http://py-enmr.cerm.unifi.it/</link>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">110234577</guid>
    <pubDate>Thu, 16 Dec 2010 12:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
    <description>
        <![CDATA[
	Dear all,<br/>
        it is our pleasure to announce that now you can create, rename, e delete projects with new filemanager GUI. You can also check easily
	the status of your jobs, download or remove it and so way.
        ]]>
    </description>
</item>

</channel>
</rss> 